<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on CS4All @ CPS</title>
    <link>http://cs4all.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on CS4All @ CPS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 14:56:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cs4all.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Partner</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/partners/become-a-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:12:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/partners/become-a-partner/</guid>
      <description>Join Us! There are three different ways to become a partner to CS4All and each have a variety of ways that you can choose to support the initiative. The expectations for each method of partnership are explained below and vary for each type of support. Please fill out the form at the bottom of the page to express your interest in becoming a partner.
Support CS4All Teachers! The teachers of CS4All are the building blocks of the initiative, they are the reason that as a school district we are able to push computer science education forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Curriculum</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/curriculum/apple-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/curriculum/apple-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>If your school has recent Apple hardware available, we endorse the free K-12 teaching and learning resources from Apple. These resources, which are part of Apple’s Everyone Can Code program, are aligned with core computer science themes, and are mapped to the relevant CSTA and ISTE Computer Science standards. Below is a description of the range of resources available that take students all the way from no coding experience to building their first apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become an Internship Supervisor!</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/programs/internship-supervisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/programs/internship-supervisor/</guid>
      <description>Becoming a Champion is easy when you have a great partner!
Chicago Public Schools offers a six-week summer internship program to high school juniors and seniors that are pursuing a career pathway in Technology. All internships are skills-based, paid and include workplace experiences that support skills development and professional career readiness. The internship provides students an expanded network of professionals, new and improved skill sets and the confidence to become practicing young tech professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS Curriculum Solutions</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs-curriculum-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs-curriculum-solutions/</guid>
      <description>

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS Opportunities Outside of School</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/students/opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/students/opportunities/</guid>
      <description>Stay up to date on a month-to-month events calendar by visiting STEM Kids.
Free Summer  Girls Who Code Summer Immersion Program (10th-11th) Coderspace Summer Program (9th-12th) Project Syncere STEM Summer Camp (6th-8th &amp;amp; 9th-12th) Museum of Science and Industry Fab Lab Summer Camp (5th-7th &amp;amp; 7th-9th) Adler Technology Summer Camp (4th-7th) BitSpace Summer Camp (6-18) Code Play Learn Summer Camps (K-7th)  After School  YouMedia (6th-12th) Blue1647 (scholarships available) Coderspace Saturday Sessions (9th-12th) Girls Who Code Club (9th-12th) Chick Tech (9th-12th) Microsoft DigiGirlz (7th-12th) Black Girls Code Chicago Chapter Events (7-17, *prices can vary) Coderdojo Chicago (7-17, suggested donation) Maker Lab Harold Washington Library (14+, 10-13 w/ adult) Adler Teen Opportunities Fermilab Students (K-12th, *prices can vary) Chicago Architecture Foundation Teens (age varies, *prices can vary) Chicago Southside Mini MakerFaire Chicago Northside Mini MakerFaire  Online  Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS Teacher Resource Repository</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs-teacher-resource-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs-teacher-resource-repository/</guid>
      <description>CPS teachers can access our resource repository, a Google Drive folder where our teachers have added resources they have created, especially lesson plans for CS curricula.
Access it here!
Due to CPS&amp;rsquo; current sharing policy, the folder is only accessible within the CPS Google Apps domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS4All Calendar</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs4all-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs4all-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science for All Events Calendar </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS4All Curriculum Guide</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/curriculum/cs4all-curriculum-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/curriculum/cs4all-curriculum-guide/</guid>
      <description>Our curriculum guide charts the alignment of our endorsed K-12 curricula to thematic strands:
 Computational Thinking Teamwork, Play, Discovery Creative Expression and Personal Safety Thinking Algorithmically Real Life Algorithms Working with Computers Innovative Design Computer Programming IT Soft Skills Being a Computer Scientist CS Knowledge and Communication          A more detailed curriculum guide is available to our teachers. This guide contains more information about how specific CS lessons align to the thematic strands listed above, as well as the CSTA and ISTE standards for CS education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS4All Grants</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs4all-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/cs4all-grants/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science for All has received several grants since the conception of the initiative. Each of these grants has played an extremely important role in propelling the CS4All initiative forward in Chicago.
CME Group has provided a grant to CS4All in order to support our efforts of significantly improving STEM educational offerings within CPS. Our mutual hope is that by giving students a quality introduction to computing in their younger years, we will better prepare them for 21st-century global society participation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS4All Staff</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/about/staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/about/staff/</guid>
      <description>Brenda Darden Wilkerson is a technology education evangelist and the Director of Computer Science &amp;amp; IT Education at Chicago Public Schools. As the founder of the original Computer Science for All initiative in 2013, her work includes building CS into CPS’ general course of study. Brenda is a graduate of Northwestern University where she studied computer science.    Curriculum Team Our new curriculum team will guide the selection and development of computer science curriculum across the district and across K-12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College &amp; Career Links</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/college-career-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/college-career-links/</guid>
      <description>General Information  U.S. Dept. of Labor – Employment and Training Administration’s career tools and scholarships Chicago Public Schools – Office of Pathways to College and Career (Post-Secondary site) College Counseling Culture – College counseling blog College Xpress Network – College planning, searches, scholarships and college admissions requirements College Illinois – Official website for the Illinois Student Assistance Commission (ISAC) The Center for Student Opportunity – Promoting higher education for first generation and other underserved college-bound students Info Careers – Career schools, top/new careers, labor market info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>CS4All was established within Chicago Public Schools by Brenda Wilkerson in 2013, providing input and inspiration to the CS4All movements around the country. Brenda Wilkerson is Senior Manager at Chicago Public Schools of Computer Science &amp;amp; Information Technology Ed., Office of College and Career Success, Computer Science for All!, and Early College and Career Education. This site is a community resource in support of that effort.
You can contact us at cs4all@cps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECS Peer Coaching</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/programs/ecs-peer-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/programs/ecs-peer-coaching/</guid>
      <description>Participants in the ECS peer coaching program are matched with a master ECS teacher to work on the following areas of teaching practice:
 Establishing an equitable classroom culture (partners, groups, questioning) Productive questioning (connections, engagement, effect, pacing) Keeping students engaged in learning (classroom norms, pacing, transitions, connections) Managing effective collaboration (teacher role, engagement) Providing appropriate feedback, both in class and on assignments (affirmation, alternatives) Managing student presentations (differentiation, equity) Formative assessment (creating, effectiveness) CS content (what is being taught, choices of pedagogy, misconceptions) Time management (deadline creep, activities) Other areas as needed  The coaching process involves a pre-visit conversation, the visit, and then a post-visit conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Career Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/parents/career-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/parents/career-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Every industry is looking for computer scientists, and with an average starting salary of $58,000, according to Forbes, and have more jobs available than students to fill the openings, every computer science student is highly lucrative. Computer science provides students with the opportunity to pursue their technical passions while also having enough freedom to express their creativity through their platform of expression. Computer science is not limiting, by being able to adapt to all mediums and being applicable to all problem areas, students can apply the lessons that they have learned through computer science to anything that they wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/parents/get-involved/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/parents/get-involved/</guid>
      <description>If you would like to learn more about the work that CS4All is doing inside of CPS and how you can involved through more hands on volunteering and participation there are several opportunities and organizations that have created opportunities for you to do so. Additionally CS4All is an initiative that thrives off of parent and community involvement, through your involvement in student computer science education students will be even more encouraged to pursue his or her path in computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Requirement</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/parents/graduation-requirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/parents/graduation-requirement/</guid>
      <description>This past winter, our district instituted the first purely computer science graduation requirement in the nation. Starting with the graduating class of 2020, all high school students must take and pass at least one full-year computer science course.
The core high school courses consists of two offerings:
 Exploring Computer Science (ECS): This course was founded on a K-12/university partnership out of Los Angeles and aims to change the stereotypes around computer science, whether they be belief systems, political, or technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hour of Code</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/resources/hour-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/resources/hour-of-code/</guid>
      <description>Code.org launched the Hour of Code in 2013 and since then students have written 11,151,730,618 lines of code. We believe heavily in using the Hour of Code to inspire students to try coding, that&amp;rsquo;s why each year during CSed week we work with and invite schools to have their students participate in the Hour of Code.
Both CSed Week and Code.org provide all of the resources that schools K-12 need to get their students ready to do an Hour of Code, regardless of whether or not they have access to a computer or if they&amp;rsquo;ve ever programmed before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Leaders</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/get-involved/business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/get-involved/business/</guid>
      <description>CS4All provides businesses, industry professionals, and other industry leaders with a way to make a huge impact on teachers and students throughout Chicago by enhancing the state of computer science education. If you or your business would like to get involved with the CS4All initiative in CPS there are several ways for you to do so. Some ways that you could get involve include:
 Hosting a professional development session at your office Hosting job shadows for teachers Hosting job shadows for students Offer internships to students Make a hardware donation, help provide technology to a school</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent &amp; Community</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/get-involved/parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/get-involved/parent/</guid>
      <description>If you would like to learn more about the work that CS4All is doing inside of CPS and how you can involved through more hands on volunteering and participation there are several opportunities and organizations that have created opportunities for you to do so. Additionally CS4All is an initiative that thrives off of parent and community involvement, through your involvement in student computer science education students will be even more encouraged to pursue his or her path in computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Your Digital Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/students/digital-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/students/digital-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>As you begin to study and pursue computing you are sure to begin to create and work on many projects. It is important that you are able to keep track of and log the projects that you work on to show off all of your hard work to potential employers, colleges, and even family and friends. These tools can be used to help you track and organize all of your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Advisory Board</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/students/student-advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/students/student-advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>The Student Advisory Board was created by CS4All to provide a student perspective on the CS4All curriculum and the student’s learning environment in order to help the CS4All team work on improving both for future computer science students. The board consists of a diverse group of approximately 10 - 15 high school students who represent various areas of the city (south, west, north) and school types (including charter and option schools) who are selected through an open application process each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit a Photo</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/educators/submit-a-photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/educators/submit-a-photo/</guid>
      <description>Submit a photo showing off your computer science class and/or your computer science students and some of the incredible projects that they work on. We will showcase some of these photos throughout our website and other social media outlets.
Follow this link to upload you photo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Advisory Council</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/educators/teacher-advisory-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/educators/teacher-advisory-council/</guid>
      <description>CS4All encourages educators to network and share their knowledge and expertise when it comes to the curricula and different teaching materials, tools, and resources that they find useful. We have assembled a Teacher Advisory Council of highly experienced and active CS4All teachers who are available to act as resources not only to the the CS4All team members but also to other teachers and administrators in the district. This council will be available to offer advice on curriculum development, framework development, new student outreach and engagement plans, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Resources</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/educators/tools-and-student-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/educators/tools-and-student-resources/</guid>
      <description> Teacher/Classroom Resources  Bootstrap - Computer science and Algebra curriculum and software Project Guts - Computer Science and Science resources CS Principles Resources Exploring Computer Science Teaching Resources Bootstrap Online Community Code.org Online Community CS10K Online Community CS4All Newsletter Archive Exploring Computer Science Curriculum Resources Computer Science Principles Curriculum Resources Computer Science Teachers Association Community National Center for Women &amp;amp; Information Technology Resources CS Bits and Bytes - NSF Newsletter highlighting innovative CS research Computer Science Education Week Google Computer Science for High School - Community and resources Google for Education - Classroom resources, student programs, and scholarships Amazon Inspire - Free service for the search, discovery, and sharing of digital educational resources Finch Robots from Chicago Public Library Google Expeditions  Student Competitions &amp;amp; Clubs  FIRST Robotics - Rookie team resources Chicago Maker Challenge Raspberry Pi Challenge National STEM Video Game Challenge Google CS First Club CodeDay Chicago - Student hackathon CPS &amp;amp; Googlepalooza Hackathon - Student hackathon Scratch Day - Typically held at West Ridge Elementary Google Code-In - Students work with an open source software organization on tasks to win prizes  Student Awards  National Center for Women &amp;amp; Information Technology Aspirations in Computing Award - High school girls can apply Illinois Technology Foundation Fifty for the Future ACM/CSTA Cutler-Bell Prize in High School Computing  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Can My Child Take CS?</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/parents/where-can-my-child-take-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/parents/where-can-my-child-take-cs/</guid>
      <description>To date, CS4All has CS programs in 89 elementary schools and 74 high schools. Use the map below to see where these schools are and to connect to the school&#39;s site to learn more about their individual computer science programs. If you do not see your child&#39;s school on the map but you would like them to learn computer science at school please fill out the form below the map to express your interest in bringing computer science to your school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why CS? Why Now?</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/parents/diversity-in-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/parents/diversity-in-cs/</guid>
      <description>Our goal with CS4All is to ensure that students across the district are afforded the opportunity to receive world-class CS instruction, regardless of the type, size, or socioeconomic status of a school’s students. This policy is designed to encourage and motivate Chicago Public School students to pursue post-secondary preparation in the various fields of computer sciences. This policy is further intended to provide direction to schools for the inclusion of appropriate computer science instruction within the curriculum in all schools and grade levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College &amp; Career Planning</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/students/college-career-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 15:44:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/students/college-career-planning/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in pursing a major in computing in college, or looking for help on making your decision, these resources can help provide you with information:
 Reasons to major in computing Preparing for a computing major Computing degrees and careers  If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to pursue computing in college one of the most important tools you can have is access to a computer. Several colleges provide students with laptops upon entering their freshman year and even more offer discounts to purchase a laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb. 24, 2016 - CPS Makes Computer Science a Graduation Requirement!</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2016-02-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2016-02-24/</guid>
      <description>On February 24, 2016 the Chicago Board of Education unanimously approved the addition of computer science as a graduation requirement for all Chicago Public Schools (CPS) students beginning with next year&amp;rsquo;s freshmen, the class of 2020. CPS has become a national leader in computer science education since Mayor Rahm Emanuel launched the Computer Science for All (CS4All) initiative for grades K-12 in December 2013.
After CPS launched the CS4All initiative in 2013, several large urban districts have replicated a curriculum and model similar to Chicago&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan. 30, 2016 - Obama Announces Support for Computer Science for All!</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2016-01-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2016-01-30/</guid>
      <description>See President Obama&amp;rsquo;s proposal for four billion in funding nationwide, and $100 million for some school districts, to provide Computer Science for All.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb. 12, 2015 - Catalyst Chicago Covers the Then &amp; Now of CS4All</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2015-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2015-02-12/</guid>
      <description>Read up on the history of CS4All and learn how schools like Lindblom are taking CS and using it as a catalyst for their students. Learn more about where we see CS4All&amp;rsquo;s trajectory going and what others have to say about our initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov. 24, 2014 - CS4All featured in the Washington Post!</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2014-11-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2014-11-24/</guid>
      <description>Read a feature on CS4All and learn more about our initiative and our plans to make computer science available to all students in the district as well as a core requirement! Great highlights of obstacles and successes, as well as a few school features, provide insight as to how our initiative has been progressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sept. 11, 2014 - Kindergartners Learning to Code!</title>
      <link>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2014-09-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 16:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cs4all.io/news-updates/2014-09-11/</guid>
      <description>Read our feature in CBS Chicago which talks about Ariel Elementary school using CS with their Kindergarten students. Learn about the initial impacts of the CS4All initiative!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>